<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Defs>
	
	<!--===================== Concepts about magic taught through the learning readout, when opportunities arise ===================-->

	<ConceptDef>
		<defName>TM_Portals</defName>
		<label>Magic - Portals</label>
		<priority>50</priority>
		<needsOpportunity>True</needsOpportunity>
		<helpText>1. Only an Arcane mage trained in Gateway magic can activate a portal.
 a. The option to activate a portal only appears when the Arcane mage has enough mana (70%) for activation.
 b. Only a map actively occupied by colonists can be selected.
 
2. Once activated, any mage can charge the portal; a portal must be charged to use, but any pawn can use it.
 a. Only one pawn at a time may use the portal; each pawn drains the portal by 5% of its maximum energy.
 c. All items are transmitted simultaneously; the cost to transfer items through a portal is 10% of its maximum energy.

3. Only mages can transfer items or deactivate a portal. A portal must be deactivated before it can be reactivated with a new target.
</helpText>
		<highlightTags>
		  
		</highlightTags>
	</ConceptDef>
	
		<ConceptDef>
		<defName>TM_Enchanting</defName>
		<label>Magic - Enchanting</label>
		<priority>52</priority>
		<needsOpportunity>False</needsOpportunity>
		<helpText>Enchanting offers mages the ability to imbue weapons and armor with enhancements.  There are a few things you should know about enchanting:

1. Only mages can enchant!  The process of enchanting requires mana, so mundane pawns will be unable to equip enchanting stones.
 
2. To enchant an item, your colony must complete the following prerequisites:
 a. Your colony must have a gemcutting workbench, research Enchanting in the research menu under the Magic tab.
 b. Gather raw magicitye; it can be found in any mineable stone, each mining strike has a chance to uncover raw magicyte.
 c. Craft enchanting stones from the gemcutting workbench.
 
3. Once you've crafted an enchanting gem of your choice, you will need a mage to perform the enchantment.
 a. With a mage selected, right click on the enchanting gem and select the option to equip the gem for enchanting
 b. Once the mage is holding the gem, right click on any weapon or apparel that is on the ground and choose to enchant. The mage performing the enchantment cannot be drafted.
</helpText>
		<highlightTags>
		  
		</highlightTags>
	</ConceptDef>

			<ConceptDef>
		<defName>TM_EnchantingII</defName>
		<label>Magic - Enchanting II</label>
		<priority>51</priority>
		<needsOpportunity>False</needsOpportunity>
		<helpText>Enchanting: Part II
		
4. Enchantments are permanent and each item may hold one enchantment of each type.  New enchantments of the same type will replace the existing 
enchantment.  Enchanting an item does not increase the value of the item.  Enchanting an item consumes the enchanting gemstone.  There is
currently no way to extract an enchantment from an item.

5. Raw magicyte (and refined gemstones) may also be purchased from select vendors. The process of deep ore mining, unfortunately, filters out
the chance to acquire raw magicyte in this manner. Users of the "quarry" can add magicyte to the extracted minerals, the recommended value is 0.4%
 
6. If you wish to drop an enchanting stone, select the mage holding the enchanting gem, right click on any open square and select the menu option
to drop the gem.

7. Item enchantments can be viewed on individual gear by selecting the item on the ground and using the "Enchanted" tab. The collective Enchantments 
affecting a single pawn can be seen in the health tab and a summary of the enchantments will be displayed under a pawn's gear tab.		
</helpText>
		<highlightTags>
		  
		</highlightTags>
	</ConceptDef>
</Defs>


